# callur

# łome GitHub

I want to work for companies that build great products and delivery quality experiences to people. I'm not interested in applications that feel like a burden to use or force them into some sort of cycle, I want to build things that matter to people and people get a genuine enjoyment out of investing their time in. At the same time I want to build applications that help people achieve what they want in life and get out of the way.

I'm not interested in being a pure backend engineer, my most enjoyable jobs have come when while implementing backend functionality I've worked with designers and frontend developers to produce a good end to end user experience. The backend is responsible for holding up the promise of a good experience: if it's slow, requires too many options or doesn't provide a feedback loop the application breaks down as an experience. I'm interested in working with MVC frameworks on the

\*nix environment. I am a big beliver in the skinny controller pattern, moving common actions out of the controller into a 'manager' which simplifies testing and usage in API endpoints. I prefer to implement the view model pattern (+ serializers) when needed to free up the logic from database models. I believe in the web, whether

it be as a delivery mechanis

for native mobile

applications or as applications themselves. With the backend MVC frameworks shomewhat decided, the attention right now is on how frontend applications should be implemented, I'm a big fan of clientside MVC frameworks consuming the application like an ordinairy API. I'm always interested in

exciting oppurtinities, locally and internationally. If you would like the chat, hit me at contact@callumj.com Skills

Ruby Developed API and full featured applications with Ruby on Rails. Worked with Sidekiq for background processing. JavaScript Developed

frontend applications in Knockout.JS, EmberJS and Backbone.js. Integrated Rickshaw.js (+ D3.js) with MVC applications for simple

metric renderings. ASP .NET Worked with ASP.NET MVC 5 (.NET 4.5) with Quartz scheduling,

Rebus worker infrastructure, Ninject, Automapper and NUnit. Objective-C Developed iPad and iPhone applications for standalone

and client-server setup. Worked with Core Data and FCModel for data persistence. **Ansible** Built simple

Ansible workflows for provisioning of application servers. **Docker** Setup Docker

application reuse, integrated with Ansible for quick container provisioning. **Amazon Web Services** 

environments for simple

Worked with EC2, Route 53 and VPC for complete application environments.

Migrated domains to Route 53 and depliyed website/assets to CloudFront on S3.

MySQL Worked with optimising queries for reduced disk space and reduced execution times AWS RDS and local.

Developer Tools Git,

# History

visual Studio,

# **Present: Extended**

วนมแท

Building personal iOS application for playback of DJ sets from SoundCloud.

iCloud support for persisting current playback position. Integration with native audio APIs via

AVPlayer API. Developed efficient process for delivering human curated playlists without

need for server (via S3), reducing scale bottlenecks.

Released to App Store with

continous support and ~400 downloads.

Developed SlimMigration, a open source project for easily migrating basic SQLite databases.

### Present: Datacom (Western Australia)

Streamlining deployment process of existing Rails application with Docker and

Ansible (to support multiple client site distribution).

Rails developer in team.

# Providing support as senior

# Present: Local startup (Western Australia)

Managing and developing client's prototype ASP.NET MVC 5 application involving

external API aggregation, fast metric aggregation and generation and dashboard.

Architected complete application layout: frontend and backend separation, continuous integration and

deployment. Developed worker system ontop of Rebus API for fast

### metric generation. 2012 - 2013: Discovr

# (Western Australia)

Part of team developing backend API for iOS application. Worked with

Rails 3.2, MySQL (AWS RDS), Sidekiq, content discovery and extraction, external catalogue integration.

Developed TrackDiscovery, a pipeline for discovering new tracks and delivering content to new users. Worked with tracking,

analysing and optimising MySQL queries while maintaing AWS RDS setup. Developed backend for a frontend application,

working with a designer to deliver story pages capable of playing SoundCloud and YouTube content. 2011 - 2013: Corporate **Governance Risk** 

(Western Australia) Part of team developing

# tracking organisation's

product for managing and risks. Worked with Rails 3.2, MongoDB (+ Mongoid), Nginx, EmberJS. **Developed AWS** 

infrastructure for international clients, with application and database redundancy. Interviewed candidates and managed remote team

(India) for delivery of additional application features.

2011: CSG (now NEC Australia) (Western Australia) (part-time during study)

Worked with team in developing first iPad application for St John's Ambulance.

Developed features for fast data entry and input of body

related events. Provided support on small

ASP.NET MVC 2 application.

## 2010: Rummble (London) (part-time during study)

First experience working in a startup.

Supported development of

Struts 2 application (Java)

Developed Rails + MongoDB based Facebook app for sourcing recommendations from Facebook friends.

Hackathon)

Upgraded Java backend and iOS application to Facebook Graph API, successfully transitioning users with auto migration flow.

Gained appreciation for clear and concise application functionality.

Education

(Part of Facebook

### 2008 - Nov. 2011: University of Western Australia

Completed Bachelors of Computer Science majoring in Web and Systems.

Studied Data Structures, Computer Networks, C and

Studied Data Structures,
Computer Networks, C and
J development.

Participated in team project
successfully delivering

Participated in team project successfully delivering external client's requirements.

Early 2010 - Mid 2010: University of East

Early 2010 - Mid 2010: University of East London
Studied Information

Security, Network Security and Programming Paradigms.

Mid 2010 - Late 2010:

Oueen Mary, University

Queen Mary, University of London

Studied Computer Image Processing, Multimedia, Distributed Networks and

Security.

Developed basic application for "spot the difference" in two images.

two images.